Hi everyone. Today my guest is Shubam
Sabu. Shoubam's track record at the
intersection of AI products and open
source is genuinely extraordinary. He's
a senior AI product manager at Google
where he works on the AI products that
millions of developers build with every
single day. His work is largely centered
around helping developers build and
deploy AI agents and providing feedback
from developers to PMs. He's also the
creator of the awesome LLM apps
repository on GitHub, which has over
105,000 stars, making it the most
popular collection of AI agent examples
ever. On top of that, he has published
two books. One on GPD3 back when it was
just released, and another on neural
search, which covers the embeddings and
vector search technology that now powers
every rack system and AI agent you've
ever used. In this episode, we'll take a
deeper look with him into all of the
cool new agentic tools that Google just
released from ADK 2.0 O and agent CLI
and how the experience of building
agents has just been upgraded. Shbam,
thank you so much for being here and
welcome to the agent factory.
>> Thank you for having me smother. It's
great to be here. Super excited to talk
to you about this.
>> So Shbam, 105,000 stars on your GitHub
repository. You know, that's just not a
vanity metric. That's actually 105,000
developers who looked at your work and
they said, you know, I need something
like this. So take us back to the
beginning. What was the original spark
behind the awesome LLM apps repository?
And then did you also ever imagine that
it could lead to you landing a PM role
at Google?
>> Short answer, no. I haven't imagined any
of this to go like that. Uh so to take
you back at the beginning when I was
experimenting with GB3 just came out and
I was experimenting with the API. I was
putting together a lot of these LLM apps
and samples that I was working with,
experimenting with it locally. Uh so I
thought like because I have all these
like samples that are like local uh that
I'm experimenting with and working with.
U maybe I should just structure it like
put it out there on GitHub and structure
it just to keep my sanity intact. So
whenever I have to reference it back
later, I have a structured place to go
and find it. uh there was the whole
point behind putting this GitHub
repository I haven't thought that it
would go go become anything like this
and few weeks later when I looked at it
like I had like five seven examples up
already and I saw like there are
thousand stars which was huge for me for
someone who hasn't got even 100 stars
before so it was a big deal and that was
the moment when I realized maybe it
isn't just me who is looking for
something like this maybe people want
stuff like this people want uh really
usable actual sample code and examples
that they can just run with and use and
learn at the same time. Uh so that that
that that was the spark that led me to
building it and keep contributing it.
Like a month later there was like 2,000
stars and in like few months it was like
5,000 stars. I was like okay this is
getting crazy. I should uh spend more
time with it. I should put more energy
to it. So I just started putting
together everything that I was
experimenting with building locally to
that GitHub repo and the idea was to
just like make it open source so that
people don't struggle with using it and
can build on top of it and make it
really really easy for people to use it
like today it has 105,000 stars 15,000
over 15,000 forks uh which is still like
all of this is unimaginable like
something that I wouldn't have thought
of before uh because and today also it
sits at like one of the top 100 most
star repos of all time and even made me
to like top 20 Python developers across
the globe multiple times put that in
list and me being not a hardcore coder
coder so it's a it's a huge deal uh and
that's that's how it all started and
that's where we are today
>> it sounds like you know you were
building publicly and you were initially
trying to solve a problem for yourself
of trying to keep a record of all the
you know fast-pacing uh stuff which was
happening at that time and it just
turned into something really big. And
then to add to that, what I think is
really fascinating is you're not just
curating uh you're also building at
Google. Uh you've written books, you've
seen the entire arc from GPD3 to where
we are now at with Asianic AI. So how
has your perspective on you know what
makes a good AI agent changed from when
you wrote that book initially to today
at Google?
>> That's an interesting question.
Previously, it wasn't even an AI agent.
AI agent like today we all know it as AI
or AI agents. It started way back with
machine learning with GB3. It introduced
the concept of a large language model
which is an AI model that we use as part
of AI agent. And 3 years ago if I go
back and look at it the entire graph was
prompt engineering. So I don't know
Smith if you remember that GPD3 UI where
you have to put in like system
instruction prompt structure it in a way
just to make sure that you get something
out of the model that you want. So
previously the art was just making sure
you get something out of the model that
you want and that that we referred as
prompt engineering. So back then if I
have to spend time like I'd spend an
afternoon getting structured JSON or uh
something like that but today it's as
easy as passing a pyic schema and it
just works. Uh so a lot has changed now
like uh back then back then like agent
was just a janky loop around a
completion call with some string
parsing. Today I have six agents running
on a chron job that does uh all the work
for me. What hasn't really changed is uh
the people who are shipping the most
useful apps are the ones who understand
their users and the problems. Uh the
model is a universal function now. So
the model is table stakes. Everybody has
the model. Model just produces whatever
you want. You don't really have to
struggle with prompt engineering and
come up with those like magic words to
get something out of the model. uh your
only job now is to shape the problem so
that the universal function that you
have as something meaningful to work
with. So everybody has access to model
but the people who are winning today or
sh out shipping the others are the
people who understand their problems
better, people who understand their
users better. Uh that was true in GB3
era as well. So your prompt is as good
as your understanding of uh the problem
that you're solving or understanding of
the users and problems that you're
working with. That's even more true now
because now everybody pretty much
everybody has access to these models and
agents. So model is table stakes
everything around this is harness which
we all sort of and in combination it
total becomes agent everybody has access
to that but what has become more
important is how do you communicate with
your agent? How do you talk to your
agent? Uh do you understand the users
that you're solving for? Do you
understand the problem that you have and
can you shape that? So all of these
skills were important today has become
more and more important. We have come
all the way from making sure uh we
hammered the model to to a way that it
can produce the output that we want uh
to an agent which is super super smart
and the only limitation now is how
creative you can get with it like how
clearly you can think about the problem.
That's where we are. I love that and I
actually like really like the take that
you have on how we went from something
super simple of prompt engineering like
you said to where we're right now at and
how there's certain skills which have
like stuck around as being super
important uh no matter which stage we
were at. So I've heard a lot about agent
CLI and I'm super excited to see you
demoing this for us. Could you explain
what exactly is agent CLI and how can
people start building with it? Yeah. So
agent CLI in agent platform is a CLI and
skills packages combined to give the
models your coding agent. You can use it
first of all you can use it with any
coding agent be Gemini CLI uh clot
codeex or any other coding agent that
you would like. But what happened before
is when you ask those coding agent to
build uh agents in ADK it might
hallucinate at times or it might come up
with buggy code but agent CLI really
fixes that. It is a combo or it is a
package of CLI uh and skills for
building, evaluating and deploying AI
agents on Google Cloud agent platform.
So everything packaged into a single
CLI. All you need to do is just like set
up install one command. Once you do this
and it will you can do it in your
terminal. It will be globally picked up
by any of your coding agents and just
like that automatically your coding
agents have access to all the internal
tools u the code base and knowledge
about ADK and building agents from there
agent CLI handles everything like
scaffolding your agents if you want to
eva use evals on cloud Google cloud
agent platform it can do that just from
like simple English prompts it can
deploy it in simple command it can add
observability can do all these things.
The simplest way to use agent CLI is
through a coding agent. But if you don't
want to use a coding agent, you can just
directly use uh CLA commands. And it
packages all these skills that you see
here. It's like seven skills package
which pretty much covers the entire
agent development life cycle. And to see
that in action, let's actually get into
the terminal and build our first agent
using a agent CLI. So what we'll do is
we'll just follow this simple tutorial
to get started with. It's a caveman
compressor. An interesting example. Uh
this agent takes verbose text and grunts
it down to caveman style summaries which
is kind of fun. Uh so to get started all
you have to do is copy this command and
run it in your terminal and then you can
open any of your coding coding agents.
As mentioned before you can use Gemini
CLI, cloud code, codeex or any other
agent. So I've already run the uvx
command to install the agent CLI. Opened
up a coding agent. Again, you can use
any coding agent that you would like.
I've opened up Gemini CLI and we can
just get started. That's all it needed.
So if I give it this prompt, use agent
CLI to build a caveman style agent that
compresses WOS text into technical
grants. It can just start executing just
like that. And you'll see it picking up
these agent skills from agent CLI
scaffold. So it is working. The install
is working fine. We'll allow it and it
will keep building. It will
automatically build the agent files and
put it in this directory. Here I've
created this agent CLI demo folder under
my desktop and all you have to do is
just like allow allow allow some
commands. So here you see it has created
this uh new folder called caveman agent
installed agent CLI used all the skills
that it wanted and in maybe less than a
minute you'll have something up and
running smith I remember you were asking
me why agent CLI in the beginning this
is uh the real use case this is what you
get out of the box pretty much
everything like along with the code you
get the environment you get everything
that you just need to get started with
uh and then you can just once it is
complete you can just ask the agent
itself to run the app via ADK web
locally. So it here we see it has
already completed it has built the
caveman agent using agent CLI all these
files are in there uh it has also tested
it out here you can see it has provided
this vos input and our caveman agent has
converted into this This is funny. And
we can also test it with a web UI. All I
have to do is run this.
>> This is actually huge. So I think just
like a couple months back, what I would
used to do when I was using Gemini CLI
and trying to build agents uh using ADK,
I would copy paste like stuff from the
ADK docs to Gemini CLI to give it more
context. But I think now I can skip all
of that because we have that
prepackaged.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And here you see by the time
you are talking smitha it has already
spinned up the web UI and it is already
running on our local host at this port.
But before we get to that let me start
the deployment process. So you can like
you can deploy it on agent engine but
you can also ask the agent what all
deployment options that you have uh to
really understand what you could do with
it. So please help me understand the
deployment options available for my
project. it will figure out and give you
all the info that you need and then you
can select which deployment option that
you would want to use. Here you see. So
it is like actually having an senior
engineer working alongside you to really
give you guidance whenever you get stuck
or it it just works for learning as
well, right? Uh let's say if I'm
deploying it for the first time in the
Google ecosystem, Google cloud ecosystem
and I don't know what my uh deployment
options are. All I can do is just prompt
it here and I get these three options.
It also tells me what it is best for,
how it works, the cost, all these
things. And then all I can say is deploy
to agent engine. If you remember, agent
engine is our deployment runtime for uh
deploying AI agents on agent platform
that we looked at it when we talked
about the resume and the ambient agents.
So it will do the deployment. It
normally takes around 5 to 10 minutes.
That's why we
uh gave it this command. Are you ready
to deploy the caveman agent to the def
environment? Yes.
And the good thing is it always asks for
explicit approval when you ask it to
interact with these external services.
Now it will automatically deploy to
agent engine in next 5 minutes. We can
come back to that. But
>> so it's it's not going to just like
power up a bunch of cloud services
without you not knowing. So that's
great.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And uh the other great thing
about it is you really don't have to
leave your terminal to get all of these
things done. Before you would have to go
to cloud console, look at the agent
engine, maybe run a few commands, go and
read the talk and even if you were using
coding agent, you have to like give
multiple docs link or connect MCP
servers and whatnot, right? It was kind
of a mess. Now, agent CLI really brings
it all together.
>> Um,
>> and obviously also all of the config
files, the YAML files, it's taking care
of all of that. Uh, in order to deploy
>> all of that and and your environment and
everything, right? Uh, so we can go to
this link, the local host with port 8080
and see this come to life. So the cool
thing about ADK is you get this nice and
sleek web UI to test your AI agents
before you put them in production. This
is available locally. This is running on
my uh local environment as we saw before
in the terminal. And here I can just
open this app to test it out. I can just
like this. You see here you see the nice
chatbot that I've got. I can send a
message hi to our caveman agent and see
what it replies. Okay, how are you
doing? Maybe and here you see on the
side panel you can see all these events
uh as we are chatting it is um taking
logs of all the events that are working
here. You can see the states, artifacts,
all these things are available which
will help a developer to get the full
understanding of how the agent is
working, what all features are available
and what they can do with it. Uh, and
let's now go back and see where our
deployment is. Is it already deployed or
not? And then I can show you what it
looks like when the agent is deployed
through agent engine. So, we got this
link. We'll just paste it in our browser
and see what that looks like in cloud
console. So to remind what we did so
far, uh we installed agent CLI open uh
Gemini coding agent Gemini CLI uh in our
terminal. Just put a simple prompt to
build the caveman agent. It was built.
Then we opened up the ADK web UI to test
it out uh all through our terminal
without leaving our terminal. We got all
of this done. We gave a simple command
to deploy it on agent engine. And our
deployment is complete. This is where we
are before we go and look at the
deployment. Let's do another cool thing
here. So the next thing that you would
want to do with your agent is maybe
evaluate, right? Evaluate uh how they
are doing. So maybe we can ask the
coding agent to come up with different
eval criteria for cavement agent and run
them for us to see how it's working. uh
and this is really important for
anything that you're putting in
production to really have eval ready and
now with agent CLI your coding agent can
do that for you
so meanwhile this command runs what we
can do is go to our browser so I just
open this link in our browser here you
can see this caveman agent being
deployed you can see the dashboard you
can see the traces identity all the
production ready features
just plugged in through a single
deployment. You even have a playground
here to test it out. Hi.
And the same thing that we saw in the
local ADK web UI is also available in
the cloud console. You can look at all
these logs here. You can see the caveman
agent replying and this service is now
accessible uh for anyone everyone. uh
you can just like share the deployment
endpoint and things could be built on
top of that. So we are here. Next thing
let's look at the status of our eval
eval evals that we asked the agent to
generate. We asked the agent to generate
like 20 eval criteria for uh we asked
the coding agent to generate 20 eval
criter lots of agents. It's like
building agents with agents generate uh
20 eval criterias. And here you see it
has generated all these eval criterias.
And the best thing about this is it
won't only generate the eval criteras
but it also test the agent against those
eval criteras. We'll take a minute or
two to do that. Uh we can come back to
it later. And the next thing that you
could really do here is extend your
agent. I want to go back to the docs and
show you how you can extend the
functionalities of your functionality of
this simple caveman agent that we built
uh through simple
prompts all the way to the bottom. We
have built the agent. We are we have
already deployed the agent on agent
engine. We are we have asked the agent
to write evals and it is already running
them for us. Next thing that you would
want to do is u add tools to your agent.
So to add a Google search tool to your
agent, all you need to do is just add
this like simple prompt and it will
automatically add Google search to your
agent. Um if you want to make your agent
workflow multi- aent and add more A2A
agents, you can use this multi- aent uh
prompt. you can build a rag agent where
you could have grounding in your docs or
in your database. So we have all these
templates which lets us u which lets
agent CLI create uh these agents in
pretty much 99% of times I should say
99% of the times u in one shot. So the
next thing that we will look is how we
can add a Google search tool. So our
caveman agent have access to current
events and it has access to the internet
which makes it even more fun. But what
you can do is actually u add any of
these tools and integrations that we
talked about here. All these tools are
available at your disposal. Here you see
the agent generated these evals tested
it for us and the good thing is all the
evals are passed. If something hasn't
passed, it will flag them as fail. And
what you would do then is again ask your
coding agent what failed and what we can
do to fix them. But the next thing that
I want to show you here is how you can
add a tool to your agent. It's as simple
as this. So it will have all the context
of uh adding a tool. What kind of tools
exist in the ADK agents ecosystem? uh
what are the syntax for adding these
tools and just works here. You see this
is adding tool in real time as we speak.
Uh and once it adds the tool we can ask
it to restart the local version to pick
up the changes.
It will automatically run a smoke test
for us. Yeah. So here you see it is uh
writing the code for adding Google
search tool and not only it writes the
code, it also does a smoke test for us.
So we know that it is working. Uh
here it is asked the question about the
latest model news and the caveman
responded in his own language which is
super cavemanish. Yeah model wars hot
buy more H100s H2 good advice of course
we need more compute. Yeah. Yeah. So
yeah overall this is working. Just to
recap we built an agent. We deployed it
on agent engine. We ran a local version
through ADK web UI to test it out. We
created evals. We added tools. All of
this in what like 10 minutes.
>> So this is super exciting. Uh it seems
that it's easier now than ever to build
AI agents and I can see a lot of
developers being really excited about
this. Especially I've noticed how easy
it is to deploy this from your local
machine where you're building it with a
coding agent like Gemini CLI directly
onto the cloud. That's awesome. I think
this is a huge gamecher. Um, you also
mentioned multi- aent systems. So, could
we look at your next demo on building a
multi- aent uh PR roster using agent
CLI? I'm super pumped for this.
>> Yeah, that's that's a fun one. Let's
just head back to our Gemini CLI and let
me paste this prompt. So, and while it
works on the prompt, let me go through
what this is. Here is what I prompted
the agent CLI, the Gemini CLI to do. Uh,
build a multi-agent PR roster using ADK
and Gemini. What it will do is create an
Streamlit app with two ADK agent. One
agent will uh just go to GitHub, analyze
any PR. All we have to do is just drop a
PR URL, pull request URL. It will go and
automatically analyze the PR for good
quality, bugs, security, performance,
all the standard things. So one agent
will just act as our code analyst or
code reviewer and the second second
agent which is the fun part will be our
roast master. Based on the analysis that
we get from our first agent what it will
do is will create a roast and a meme
prompt for nanobana to generate an
image. So that meme prompt will go into
the nanobana gemini flash image model
and it will generate a meme at the end.
So this is how the workflow will
hopefully work once agency will generate
uh the thing for us
and here it is giving us like some
options you can choose like any of these
options like I'll go with this streamlet
orchestration
and then
it will run for a few minutes and create
an app. What to save us uh some time
what I already did is prompted it before
uh this call and created the app saved
it to a GitHub repo. Let's look at the
code and also deployed it through agent
CLI. Uh then we can look at the deployed
version and see how it really works and
maybe smother you can give me a PR that
you want me to roast that you want our
agent to roast and we can have some fun.
>> Sounds good. I actually have like two
PRs pulled up which would be great to
roast which I recently created. So yeah.
>> So the as mentioned this is how it would
work. It also created sh on the top. It
also created a readme for me to explain
to you guys what this app or this a
multi- aent app would do. We have a code
analyst which is analyzing the code
which is feeding into the roast master
and roastmaster writes jokes meme prompt
and give a verdict just like a score on
how good the PR is and then in the end
based on the meme prompt the nanobanana
image model Gemini image model will
generate the meme for us. So this is
what the deployed version or the fully
built up app looks like simple prototype
but really fun idea. Uh all you have to
do is just enter your Gemini key here.
GitHub token optional. If you want you
can put it here. Depends on the traffic
limiting. And all we need to do is just
drop a PR link. And let me share like
what this PR is about. Like this was the
this is the PR that we got from ADK
samples repo. Smithera, you created
this. Let's see what it comes up with.
Uh this is interesting. I'm excited
about this one.
>> I'm very curious to see this being
roasted. I've honestly not had any of my
PRs roasted besides obviously from other
software engineers. So, let's see. It'll
be nice to get it roasted by an actual
AI agent.
>> Awesome. Awesome. And the roast is
already in. We ran the PR. It reviewed
it just like any technical reviewer
would.
So, code quality looking good. Not a lot
of logical issues and bugs. This is
looking good as well. So pretty good,
Smitha. Like you got a 9.2 out of 10.
>> Nine out of two. I think that's great.
>> Yeah. Nine out of 10. 9.2 out of 10.
Pretty good. Pretty good. Let's look at
the roast and you tell me if this is
funny or not.
>> Okay.
So,
>> uh, calling load.env twice in the coding
environment of checking if you is
checking
if you lock the front door, walking to
your car, and then going back to check
again while your house is in your car
because of your error handling. Okay.
Okay, fair enough.
>> Did you know about this one?
>> Um,
no. So, setting Oh, I set the maps API
key equals to no API found instead.
Yeah, I should have used like a normal,
you know.
>> Interesting that you didn't,
>> but yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. This this is funny.
>> Gracefully when you can gaslight the MCP
tool into an o midlife crisis at
runtime. Okay, fair enough.
>> Hard coding Gemma. Not your fault. It's
a very good model. So, I'll go with
that.
>> Yeah, but this is funny.
>> That's true.
>> Interesting. Okay. Now look at the me
let's look at the meme that it
generated.
>> Okay.
>> Fair enough.
>> Final verdict is here. You build a
Ferrari but try to fuel it with a sticky
note that says gasoline not found which
is a reference to this one. It's funny.
>> Oh my god. Okay. This was a really good
roast.
>> So hopefully the agent is working. Agent
CLI is doing its thing and we
successfully created our first multi-
aent app without even getting into an
IDE. So we did all of this without
getting into an ID all from terminal
coding agent and agent CLI to the
working app that is deployed uh online
which is pretty crazy and pretty insane.
If you would have asked me like can you
do this like if you would have asked me
6 months ago is it possible I would like
maybe but now we can do it uh which is
super crazy and interesting.
>> This is so cool and I think this would
be great for people to check out. Is
this something that they can build using
your prompt? Uh is that is this prompt
available on the ADK docs website? Uh,
so we'll be open sourcing the GitHub
repo that we looked at. And what we'll
do is just like drop the prompt in there
because here's the code. Prompt history
is the new code. All you need is prompt
to regenerate the code.
>> Nice. Okay. Link in the description box
below if you're interested in also
getting your PRs for roster like me. So
you can check that out and build it
yourself.
Google Cloud Next just ended and Google
announced some really massive updates
and you at the forefront of this. So
let's talk a little bit about ADK 2.0 uh
building production grade autonomous
agents with ADK and then also super cool
the new Asian CLI in Gemini Enterprise
Asian platform. What does the new
framework unlock for developers?
>> Yeah, so we introduced quite a few
things at Google Cloud Next this year
and one of the most fascinating ones is
ADK 2.0. Something that I'm genuinely
excited about. Uh let me walk you
through some of the interesting things
that comes with ADK 2.0. So first one
that you see on the screen is
craft-based agent workflows. Uh now why
do you need graph-based agent workflows
when you can just stuff uh everything in
an agent or a multi- aent you have like
your instruction model and tools and put
it it has been working for a while right
uh but before you would define what
would happen previously is you would
define your multi- aent workflow mostly
through prompts. it worked but then you
would see your agent start taking
shortcuts after several turns or start
becoming lazy what some people would
call okay my agent has become lazy I
have all these context in but by the
time it gets to fifth or seventh turn it
forget what it did in the first turn or
it forget that has access to some of the
tools so that that's the problem that
most of the agents suffer in production
environments uh it would forget the
rules it would forget the tools that it
would have access to but With
graph-based workflows, what you can do
is now explicitly draw the flow of your
agent. Uh what that means is the parts
that need to be deterministic can stay
deterministic like compliance checks or
o where you don't really need an
intelligence or uh an agent to really
jump in. It's a straightforward logic
which needs to stay as is. And it is
very important that uh the logic stays
deterministic and does not change with
agent uh running it for five times or
seven times or 100 times right uh and
the parts where you want the model's
judgment those are reasoning nodes and
that's where you could have the model
decide and dynamically take those
decision decisions. So the same workflow
gives you access to both kind of logics
which you can put together and have it
run in your production environment. It's
a pretty clean pattern once you see it.
You get the flexibility of an agent
along with the deterministic uh workflow
or the reliability of function where you
need it. The second thing that I want to
show you is the changes that we made to
agent runtime. Uh two features that I'm
really excited about is ambient agents
and resume agents. And why do they
matter? So most of the agent demos that
you would see are 30 secondond demos or
2 minute demos where uh you you'll see
agent running in a loop for a minute or
two and then it does the task like uh it
it it completes the task and then just
like turns off. Uh but this is way far
from the production reality. Production
agents sometimes have to run for hours
and hours and maybe days at times. Uh
when a user asks something, the agent
calls a few tools, it answers done.
Production doesn't really look like
that. Production environment normally
has drop connections, services that go
down, some events that are firing at 2
a.m. workflows that span hours or days.
Uh so these are two features that help
any production agent survive that
reality. Uh let's look at the resume
agent first. So what what that really
is? Resume is actually what it sounds
like. If your agent gets interrupted, a
network drops, a service goes down or
whatever, it picks up where it actually
left off, you just flip a flag on top of
app config and it just works. It tracks
which tools already ran, skips them,
continues from the break. Before you
would before you would have to restart
everything from scratch, but now your
agents can just resume where they left
off. It's pretty cool.
>> It's really cool. I mean there it's just
like one line of code or like one flag
that you need to track.
>> It's just one flag. Yeah, it's just this
like is resumable true. That's that's
all you need to do and your agents can
resume at specific intervals when
something breaks. Now moving on to the e
even cooler part the ambient agents. So
I guess uh all of you might have heard
about open claw miss agents all these
like autonomous agents that run for days
and days like I myself run an agent team
like 60 AI agent team using open claw it
runs 24/7 doing all kind of stuff for me
so how do you build something like that
which is customized for your enterprise
for your environment that can do the
specific job reliably reliably being the
key word here uh that can do the
specific job for you reliably in your
production environment. Int agents is
the way to do that. These are the agents
that these are actually so I I would
want to take take a step back here like
normally you would have an agent you
would run it in production and you would
have like specific things to do but
agents are only as smart as your trigger
to it right you would want these agents
to autonomously execute. You would want
these agents to decide and have like
some trigger events which execute or
trigger them. Uh these are the agents in
agents are the agents that react to
those events without you prompting them.
If you are prompting them, maybe your
agent is not that intelligent. But when
your agent is deciding to execute
themselves based on certain triggers, it
is becoming more like human. is becoming
more ambient and intelligent or more re
proactive than reactive. Uh so with
ambient agents what you can do is you
can have them triggered to specific
events. It could be a popup sub message
coming in in your agent runs. A file
lands in your cloud storage or in your
local drive and it runs certain agent
workflows or there's a chron job which
you can set and at that specific time
you can your agents or agent team or
whatever your logic is uh it runs
automatically. So you get concurrency
limits, retries, dead letter cues, all
of that out of the box. before you have
to write all of this yourself and even
with that you would not really have
something that would be proactive in
nature and the last thing that I want to
uh talk about is ADK's support for
multiple languages. ADK is one of the
frameworks which is true multil-
language in nature. We have Python, we
have typescript, we have Go and Java. So
really meeting developers where they
are. You don't really need to learn
Python or move everything to Python to
use a production grade agent workflow.
You can use it in the language that you
like or you can use it in the language
that your existing workflows are. Uh
that really opens up a lot of teams who
weren't going to rewrite the stack for
building agents. Now anyone and everyone
can just build production agents uh
using these um languages using the
languages that they would like.
>> I think the next I can just envision so
many developers being excited about all
of these SDKs for ADK now. Uh and also I
just love the look of the new adk.dev
website. It's great.
>> Awesome. Thank you so much. And all of
these are open source. So if you are a
geek or if you are really interested in
looking at the source code, all you need
to do is just like click any of these
repo and you can actually see the source
code. So all of these repos are open
source. You can look at the source code
and you can build an extend on top of
this framework as well. That's the cool
thing about ADK that I really really
like. And the next thing that I want to
talk to you about is the open ecosystem
that we have built around ADK. So what
we did is actually went out and ask
developers the tools that they would
want to use. Not just Google tools uh
anything and everything that they would
want to use with their agents. So what
we did is we put together an open
ecosystem of tools and plugins which you
can use with ADK with your ADK agents
with just a line of code or a few lines
of code. Right. Um, Shbam, you know,
looking through your recent publications
on X, which you're doing a great job of,
by the way.
>> Thank you.
>> And I see a lot of your posts going
viral all the time. So, you've been
dropping some serious knowledge bombs. I
want to dig into a few of your core
philosophies, especially your thoughts
on Open Claw and what it's like uh being
a PM building AI for AI as you've
mentioned many times.
>> Yeah, interesting. So, let's start with
the open claw one. Uh just for the
context for people who don't know I run
a six AI agent team with open cloth that
works for me 24/7 pretty much handling
anything that I do outside Google so
managing my social media newsletter. Um
there is an engineering agent called
Ross who actively manages the awesome
LLM apps open source repo. He makes sure
all the PR
>> friends inspired I have to ask.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So yeah fun story. It
all started with Monica being my chief
of staff. So main agent uh when I was
creating uh installing open claw uh it
starts with the first agent which is
your main agent. I was like what should
be my first agent? It's like okay
because I really like friends in the
office. I was like let it be Monica. So
Monica became that's how Monica became
my chief of staff. I did not started uh
with the idea of running multi- aent
team but as the use cases expanded as we
had agents had more context it's me and
my agent working through the process of
deciding how our agent orc looks like or
what our agent or should look like uh
and that's the fun part right uh when
you start with something like open claw
you are so much bought into the hype
cycle you look at all the fancy de demos
on x and YouTube and you're like okay
this is the thing like I'll install open
claw and it will change my life. I'll
just so people install it, they fire up
their first agent. Um, and from the
get-go they started asking some very
specific questions and get garbage
output, right? They expect magic but get
mediocre output and then they blame the
framework. They're like, "Oh no, it's
not great. It's not working." And I see
these kind of people operating in two
extremes. One is people who would not
give any context. They are super
excited, pumped because they're directly
coming from X and YouTube. They're like,
"Okay, I'll do this. Install, get
started." And that's like, "Oh, this
does not work for me." Because you
haven't given any context to your agent
or to your model. It does not know
anything specific about you. It's a
generic model. It's a generic agent. So,
expect generic answers. And then there
are people on the other side of extremes
which will be like, "Okay, let me give
this agent context. let me dump
everything that I have on me or my
company all the like 5 10 100 files onto
the agent then you're doing context load
so treat agents like your h like a human
because when you do the context explode
it becomes really really diff difficult
for the agent to figure out uh what are
you specifically looking for and it
becomes really really difficult for
agent uh to figure out like what is the
specific uh uh information that really
matters the agent drowns in context, it
cannot really tell tell what matters
from what it. So the fix is really
simple here. It's pretty much how you
would onboard an intern or a new
employee. You don't dump the entire
company's information uh to them on day
one. You tell them who you are, what you
do, what you need uh from them. You
start simple, you start slow and then
you build from there and there on,
right? You slowly build on top of that.
the agents learn through you. The the
best way that I found this to be working
is let the agent interview you, ask you
follow-up question to learn about you.
And that's the process uh that worked
with me and Monica. When I created
Monica, she started asking me question,
what can I do for you? What do you like?
What do you don't like? And slowly
giving this very specific context, she
started building something called soul
file. Her personality. So soul soul file
is a very specific file which helps
agent to decide what their personality
is and through this conversation Monica
automatically start adding things adding
things in her soul file and whatever
she's learning for on me or about me she
started putting it together in user MD
file. So the agent is already very
smart. It's how you deal with them.
They've already started like she's
already started figuring out how to
structure the information, where to put
what and how to make sense out of these
things. But the only thing that really
mattered here is the specific context
that you give to your agent. So treating
your open claw agents as an employee is
the only fix. It seems difficult, but it
is not really that difficult. It is just
like talking to your agents, onboarding
them as a real employee. So based on
what you're saying, it seems that
communication is more important than
ever. Now, a lot of people assume that,
you know, when you're working with AI
agents or working with AI in general,
you don't have to communicate or
overcommunicate like you would when
you're dealing with humans, but that
seems to not be the case. It seems that,
you know, you do want to overcommunicate
and communication is more important than
ever.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I mean to normally
summarize whenever I tell these things
to people like soft skills are becoming
more important than you would think.
Basic skills like communication,
understanding the problem, user empathy,
all of these are becoming really really
important because the technical part for
agents is either being solved or getting
solved. Uh but the only part that would
remain is how you would interact with
them, how you would deal with them. Just
like the simple example that we saw with
setting up the openclaw agent Monica,
right? Uh it could be worse or it could
be really good depending on how you
communicate with them, how you interact
with them. So that's really the key
here.
>> You're also a senior AI product manager
at Google, but you're specifically
working in what people call, you know,
the AI of AI space. Uh building AI dev
tools that are explicitly designed to
build other agents. So what is it like
managing products where you know the end
user isn't just a human developer but
another AI and can you talk a little bit
more about that?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So something started
shifting almost uh last year or like the
end of last year when the users of your
product are not only just humans,
they're also agents. Because when we
build all these sophisticated systems,
what would you expect to happen next?
Right? The agents will build agents
themselves, right? And um in this
episode itself we talked about agents
like the Gemini CLI with agent CLI using
tools deploying on agent engine. There
was no human interaction between uh
human interaction required for using
those services. There was no human
interaction required for me to build
agents to deploy agents to run evals.
All of them were agents building agents.
Right? Uh so when we are designing these
products we have to keep in mind that
humans are not the only user anymore. Uh
and that changes a lot of things. Uh
human user would tolerate a little bit
of slow onboarding. They may uh read a
help text when they are confused. Uh but
when it comes to an agent they just
parse through the first thing that they
see. Every interface you design has to
work for humans as well as AI agents.
Let's have some fun. Rapid fire round.
I'll give you a statement and you tell
me agree, disagree, or it's complicated.
And then also you give me a quick reason
why. Ready? Let's go. Yeah.
>> Rag is dead and fine-tuning is the
future.
>> Damn.
I I would say the wrong it's a it's a
wrong framing. It used to make sense a
year ago. I would reframe it as
uh rag versus long context because
Karpati's LLM Viki I'm not sure if
you're following but recently Karpati's
introduc Karpati introduced this idea of
LLM Viki which is kind of your second
brain which structures everything that
you've been doing and reading uh and it
showed how you can skip rag with long
context so I would say the debate is
more around rag versus long context now
and yes it's complicated
>> the best AI agent architecture ure is
the simplest one that works
>> 100%. Like I've reviewed a lot of uh LLM
apps, LLM chat apps, AI assistant, AI
agents over the course of last 2 years.
The ones that gets most popular are the
ones that have the simplest
architecture. So people should be able
to run it. They should be able to
understand the code that it has uh all
of that in the easiest way possible. So
simplest architecture always wins. Open
source AI models will surpass
proprietary models within two years.
>> Complicated uh on specific benchmarks.
Maybe open source is catching up in a
big way. So it is getting better and
better what we saw with Quinn and Gem
Gemma 4. But I would envision a future
where 80% of your use cases would be
done by open source model. But still you
would rely on frontier closed source
model for 20% of the use cases which
might not be something that everybody
need but which would be something that
is like state-of-the-art highly complex
logical reasoning task you would still
rely on uh closed source models so
complicated but open source is getting
there
>> okay I think that's like a very hot
topic so a lot of people will be
interested every developer needs to
understand embeddings and vector search
>> I agree uh so if you're building
anything with memory retrieval
personalization you're touching
embedding you really don't need to be a
math wizard to understand embedding I'm
not asking you to like understand from
static stat statistical point of view
but at least understand the core
concepts uh at least understand what
changes when you change the chunk size
or when hybrid search beats vector
search just having a basic understanding
of these concepts why cosign similarity
is not always the best metric all these
things uh makes a lot of sense even
specifically more so in the agent world
where memory is the key layer where
retrieval is more important than ever
agree strongly agree that people should
understand and really learn about
embeddings vector databases vector so
it's debatable but embeddings yes 100%
>> AI agents are overhyped and most use
cases just need a good prompt
>> it's a rich coming from me uh Yes,
most use cases can just do with a good
prompt to uh single API call. You don't
really always need an AI agent for
everything. I know it's a hot topic and
everybody just wants to build AI agent
for anything and everything that they
want to do. Just like for caveman, we
built an agent. We did not have to, but
just to show a concept, uh we did. But
you don't really have to build agent
every time. Like if you can get away
with a simple API call, start with that.
If it's a simple workflow, that's that's
all you need. Start simple and decide
based on the data where where the data
leads you or where the problem leads you
based on the problem build complexity.
Don't start with complex multi- aent
workflow based on again what you see
from X or YouTube or like lot of people
talking about it. Not always you need
all those like complex things. So start
simple. You don't really need agents for
anything and everything that you're
doing. Just a simple model call will
mostly do the thing with a good prompt
and then if you need go and build
agents.
>> This is like a huge one even for me. I
have to keep reminding myself even if
I'm building something like a demo not
everything needs like 10 different
agents running at the same time. The
biggest bottleneck in AI right now isn't
the models it's evaluation.
>> One yes 100%. It becomes more true when
you are building uh complex agents which
is not just the models but models plus
tools plus context. So it is interacting
with a multiple components and there are
like multiple layers involved and most
of our evals these days are mostly vibes
wipes based. Okay, this looks good this
because to be honest there is there
there hasn't been a standard way to
evaluate agents or evaluate uh these
workflows. uh but a lot of these
technologies and products are built in
that direction and it is getting more
and more important that's one thing that
we saw in our agent step uh caveman
agent demo where we asked it to write
eval criteria so eval are very very
important I would highly recommend to
evaluate your agents before putting them
into production don't just fly uh by
good wipes okay this looks good and let
me put it in production because high
chances that somewhat something could
break in production you would not even
know what caused the error uh for these
agent workflows.
>> And then to end it off, I always ask all
our guests this one question. So what is
the one AI tool, framework or concept
that you could never give up?
>> Now if you would have asked me like 2
months ago, it would be very different.
Now I would say like my AI agents. Uh so
my AI agents is my interface to any and
every AI tool that I use. uh I just like
ping Monica or my other AI agents we
want to do this and they figure out
whatever tools that they they want to
use which also gets into something that
we talked about that all these products
are being mostly more and more used by
agents and not just humans. Uh so my AI
agents is something that I cannot really
live without and can cannot give up
because they are my interface to pretty
much everything that I'm building these
days. Shbam, this has been an incredible
episode. Thank you so much for coming to
the agent factory.
>> Thanks. It was great to be here. Thank
you for having me. Uh, if you want to
build what I showcased and more, check
out adk.dev and agent CLI in agents
platform. That's your way to go.
I'll be linking everything we mentioned
in the description box below along with
a bunch of viral articles that Shubam
has written on things like the five
Asian skill design patterns as well as
the complete developers guide to
building ADK Asians with skills. Check
out this next episode to see all the
cool stuff you can build with Gemini 3
along with Gemini CLI.